<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Breathing Games Dev Diary</title>
    <link>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Breathing Games Dev Diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 11:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://spirometervr.github.io/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9: Game polishing &#43; 3rd mini game concept reveal!</title>
      <link>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-9/</guid>
      <description>This week we have been iterating on the polishing of our two mini games, Treasure Hunter and Fruit Fall, based on instructor feedback. Minor camera changes were added to improve the visual feedback as the player propels the boat forward in Treasure Hunter. In Fruit Fall a new fruit targeting feature was added to make it easy for players to see which fruit they were aiming at.
We created a quick proof of concept for our third mini game, The Void, which we would like to add to round off our breathing game selections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8: ZOOM is the new USC</title>
      <link>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-10/</guid>
      <description>Spring has sprung, and the break is done. Since our last post a lot has rapidly changed in response to the novel coronavirus pandemic rapidly spreading across the world. Zoom meetings are the new normal. USC has updated the requirement now for all courses to be switched to online for the remainder of the semester. The campus is now locked down for students and non-essential employees, Commencement has been cancelled and students living in on campus housing are not allowed to return from their spring break travels to pack and move out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8: ZOOM is the new USC</title>
      <link>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-8/</guid>
      <description>Spring has sprung, and the break is done. Since our last post a lot has rapidly changed in response to the novel coronavirus pandemic rapidly spreading across the world. Zoom meetings are the new normal. USC has updated the requirement now for all courses to be switched to online for the remainder of the semester. The campus is now locked down for students and non-essential employees, Commencement has been cancelled and students living in on campus housing are not allowed to return from their spring break travels to pack and move out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7: Midterm Presentations &#43; COVID-19 = :-(</title>
      <link>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-7/</guid>
      <description>This week, in response to the novel coronavirus pandemic rapidly spreading across the world, USC required all courses to be switched to online until mid April. To adjust to this change our midterm presentation for class was switched to a walkthrough video showing the current state of our VR breathing mini games.
The change in course instruction format to online, plus the recent closure of the campus buildings to help mitigate the spread of the virus, will affect some teams more than others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6: Prototyping continued...</title>
      <link>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-6/</guid>
      <description>The process of building out each mini game continues. This week we took the time to integrate the use of the custom Digital Spirometer into or Unity projects. WIth the help of Unity OSC script, a headache and a lot of &amp;ldquo;Why is this not working!&amp;rdquo; our team finally found success. We now can use our inhalations on the digital spirometer to propel the boat forward in the scene of the Treasure Hunter game!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5: Pivots &amp; Prototyping</title>
      <link>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-5/</guid>
      <description>This week the process of prototyping our new mini games is in full swing. After speaking with Professor Marientina &amp;amp; Dr. Vangelis our mini games have pivoted a bit to the following:
   name description inhale exhale     Treasure Hunter You&amp;rsquo;re the wind slow down accelerate   Fruit Fall Knock fruit down from the trees collect a pebble blow pebble at fruit   Save the Village Be the enemy or the savior collect air/water spray fire/water    Building the scene</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: Dev Environment Setup &amp; Management Change</title>
      <link>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week we lost our Production Manager. That being said, we have elected a new PM and are still full steam ahead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this posting, we are stepping back a bit to review the development environment setup for the breathing games. Without further ado&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Field trip to CHLA</title>
      <link>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To become more familiar with the specific breathing protocol that is used by the children, this week the team took a little field trip to the Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Los Angeles. We met with 6 doctors. It turned out that the doctors thought our VR game was going to be designed around the diagnostics protocol which each patient has to first perform at the clinic before beginning their daily protocol. This was different from Dr. Vangelis&amp;rsquo; expectation of our team designing the VR experience to focus on the daily protocol, so he took the time to clarify and make sure the CHLA doctors were all onboard with our team designing for the daily protocol instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Game Idea &amp; Team Tools</title>
      <link>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It begins!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a sad note, this past week one team member had to leave the course due to a class schedule change. On a happier note, our team space was set up in the USC Creative Media and Behavioural Health lab. On top of this received two Oculus Go and 3 custom made spirometers, designed by Dr. Vangelis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: The Breathing Game Blog</title>
      <link>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spirometervr.github.io/article/post-week-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the start of our team blog. This space is for you to be part of our team&amp;rsquo;s journey on the game development process during the Spring 2020 Augmented, Virtual &amp;amp; Mixed Reality course at USC (CSCI 538). Our team has an amazing opportunity to work on building games to make the breathing therapy process more interactive and fun for kids at the Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>